A Guide to the Henry Luce Foundation records, Clare Boothe Luce Program FA1725
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation records, Clare Boothe Luce Program
1986-2014
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation
FA1725
9.87 Cubic Feet 26 letter-sized document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
The Henry Luce Foundation was established by Henry R. Luce in 1936. As a New York-based nonprofit organization, the Luce Foundation awards grants in American Art, Asian studies, Higher Education, Theology, and supports the Clare Boothe Luce Program for women in science, mathematics, and engineering.
Women in science; Grants -- Evaluation
- Designated Grant Files, 1988-2000; 1; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes grant files and reports for the first grouping of American educational institutions that were invited to participate in newly established Clare Boothe Luce Fund.
  - Boston University, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Boston University - Report, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Colby College, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Colby College - Report, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Creighton University, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Creighton University - Report, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fordham University, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fordham University - Report, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Georgetown University, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Georgetown University - Report, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Marymount University, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Marymount University - Report, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Mount Holyoke College, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mount Holyoke College - Report, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - St. John's University, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - St. John's University - Report, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Santa Clara University, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Santa Clara University - Report, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Seton Hall University, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Seton Hall University - Report, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Trinity College, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Trinity College - Report, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - University of Notre Dame, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - University of Notre Dame - Report, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Villanova Preparatory School, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Villanova Preparatory School - Report, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Visiting Professorship Program, 1986-1991; 2; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - Brown University - Jacqueline Jones, 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Columbia University - Martha Hyde, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Harvard University (Declined), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - New York University - Dorothy Nelkin, 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - University of Chicago (Withdrawn), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill - Patricia Lamb, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Yale University - Grace Wahba, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Invited Grant Files, 1988-2014; 3; 8.73 Cubic Feet 23 letter document boxes
  - Alverno College - Undergraduate Scholarship, 1998-2012 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Amherst College - Environmental Geoscience Professorship, 1997-2011 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Bard College - Environmental Science Professorship, 1995-2000 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Bard College - Undergraduate Women in Science Scholarships, 1999-2007 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Barry University - Graduate Fellowships in Biological Science, 1996-2007 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Benedictine University - Undergraduate Scholarship for Women in Science and Engineering, 1998-2002 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Boston College - Graduate Fellowships, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Boston College - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Boston College - Biology Professorship and Graduate Fellowships, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Boston College - Biology Professorship, 1998-2003 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Bowdoin College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1997-2001 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Brown University - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Bryn Mawr College - Mathematics Professorship, 1994-2001 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Bucknell University - Chemical Engineering Professorship, 1992-1997 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Bucknell University - Chemistry Professorship, 1999-2003 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - California Institute of Technology - Graduate Fellowships, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - California Institute of Technology - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1995 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - California Institute of Technology - Graduate Fellowships, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - California Institute of Technology - Geobiology Professorship and Graduate Fellowships, 1999-2006 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Carleton College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1994-2001 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Carnegie Mellon University - Graduate Fellowships in Science and Engineering, 1992-2006 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Carnegie Mellon University - Graduate Fellowships, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Carnegie Mellon University - Graduate Fellowships, 2004-2012 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Case Western University - Graduate Fellowships, 1992-2001 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Catholic University of America - Graduate Fellowships, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Catholic University of America - Graduate Fellowship in Biomedical Engineering, 1996-1998 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Catholic University of America - Graduate Fellowship in Biomedical Engineering, 1999-2003 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Clark University - Graduate Fellowships, 1995-2001 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - College of Saint Benedict - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2009 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - College of Saint Scholastica - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - College of the Holy Cross - Chemistry Professorship, 1989-1992 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - College of the Holy Cross - Undergraduate Scholarship, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - College of the Holy Cross - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2002 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - College of William and Mary - Graduate Fellowships, 1997-2004 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - College of Wooster - Physics Professorship, 1999-2006 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Colorado School of Mines - Undergraduate Scholarships and Graduate Fellowships, 1995-2001 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Columbia University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Cornell University - Graduate Fellowships, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Cornell University - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1999 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Cornell University - Graduate Fellowships, 2001-2007 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Dartmouth College - Engineering Professorship and Graduate Fellowships, 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Dartmouth College - Engineering Professorship and Graduate Fellowships, 2001-2008 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Dartmouth College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2003-2010 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - DePaul University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1993-1999 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - DePaul University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2000-2003 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - DePaul University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2004-2008 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Duke University - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1994 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Duke University - Graduate Fellowships, 1998-2004 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Emory University - Mathematics and Computer Science Graduate Fellowship, 1993-1996 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Emory University - Graduate Fellowships, 1998-2001 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Fairfield University - Undergraduate Scholarship, 1993-1996 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Fairfield University - Undergraduate Scholarship, 1997-2004 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Gallaudet University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1996-2001 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Georgia Institute of Technology - Graduate Fellowships, 1997-2004 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Gonzaga University - Biology Professorship, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Gonzaga University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1994-1999 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Grinnel College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1994-2001 (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Grove City College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2000-2009 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Gustavus Adolphus College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2003 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Harvard University - Physics Graduate Fellowships, 1994-2001 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Harvey Mudd College - Chemistry Professorship, 1992-1998 (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Harvey Mudd College - Computer Science Professorship, 1998-2004 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Harvey Mudd College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2006-2013 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Hope College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2003-2005 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Institute for Advanced Study - Postdoctoral Fellow, 1989-2001 (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - John Carroll University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - John Carroll University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1995-1999 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - John Carroll University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2002 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - John Carroll University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2003-2011 (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Graduate Fellowship, 1993-1999 (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Graduate Fellowship, 2001-2013 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Graduate Fellowship, 2004-2012 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Graduate Fellowship, 2007-2013 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Kalamazoo College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Kalamazoo College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2003-2013 (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - Kings College - Undergraduate Scholarship, 1996-2001 (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - Lawrence University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1996-1999 (Box 12, Folder 110)
  - Loyola Marymount University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1993-1996 (Box 12, Folder 111)
  - Loyola Marymount University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 112)
  - Loyola Marymount University - Undergraduate Scholarship, 1999-2009 (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - Loyola University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1992-1997 (Box 12, Folder 114)
  - Loyola University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1997-2002 (Box 12, Folder 115)
  - Loyola University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2001 (Box 12, Folder 116)
  - Lynchburg College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1998-2000 (Box 12, Folder 117)
  - Lynchburg College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2001-2005 (Box 12, Folder 118)
  - Macalester College - Physics and Astronomy Professorship, 1995-1999 (Box 13, Folder 119)
  - Marquette University - Biology Professorship, 1989-1992 (Box 13, Folder 120)
  - Marquette University - Biology Professorship and Undergraduate Scholarships, 1993-1997 (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - Marquette University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1998-2000 (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - Marquette University - Biomedical Engineering Graduate Fellowships, 1999-2003 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - Marquette University - Biomedical Engineering Graduate Fellowships, 2003-2004 (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Graduate Fellowships, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 125)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Graduate Fellowships, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 127)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Graduate Fellowships, 1994-1996 (Box 13, Folder 128)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Graduate Fellowships, 1997-1999 (Box 13, Folder 129)
  - Mississippi University - Mathematics Professorship, 1994-2001 (Box 14, Folder 130)
  - Mount St. Mary's College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 131)
  - Mount St. Mary's College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1997-2000 (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Mount St. Mary's University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2006-2013 (Box 14, Folder 133)
  - National Technical Institute for the Deaf, Rochester Institute of Technology - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1997-2001 (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Newman University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1997-2001 (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Northwestern University - Graduate Fellowships, 2000-2003 (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Northwestern University - Chemistry Professorship, 2006-2014 (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Undergraduate Scholarships and Graduate Fellowships, 1996-2000 (Box 15, Folder 138)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Graduate Fellowships, 2004-2013 (Box 15, Folder 139)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Graduate Fellowships, 2006-2013 (Box 15, Folder 140)
  - Pepperdine University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1993-1999 (Box 15, Folder 141)
  - Pepperdine University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2001-2004 (Box 15, Folder 142)
  - Princeton University - Chemistry Professorship, 1989-1994 (Box 15, Folder 143)
  - Princeton University - Graduate Fellowship, 1995-2005 (Box 15, Folder 144)
  - Purdue University - Graduate Fellowship, 1993-199 (Box 15, Folder 145)
  - Purdue University - Graduate Fellowship, 2001-2004 (Box 16, Folder 146)
  - Purdue University - Graduate Fellowships, 2003-2009 (Box 16, Folder 147)
  - Purdue University - Graduate Fellowships, 2007-2012 (Box 16, Folder 148)
  - Regis College - Undergraduate Scholarship, 1996-2001 (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - Regis University - Chemistry Professorship, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 150)
  - Regis University - Professorship and Undergraduate Scholarships, 1995-2001 (Box 16, Folder 151)
  - Regis University - Professorship and Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2001 (Box 16, Folder 152)
  - Regis University - Undergraduate Scholarship, 2003-2008 (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute - Graduate Fellowship, 1992-1999 (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute - Graduate Fellowships, 2000-2004 (Box 16, Folder 155)
  - Rice University - Undergraduate Scholarships and Graduate Fellowships, 1993-1999 (Box 17, Folder 156)
  - Rice University - Graduate Fellowships, 2000-2009 (Box 17, Folder 157)
  - Rockefeller University - Graduate Fellowships, 1993-2003 (Box 17, Folder 158)
  - Rockhurst University - Graduate Fellowship, 1995-1999 (Box 17, Folder 159)
  - Rockhurst University - Chemistry Professorship, 2000-2006 (Box 17, Folder 160)
  - Rockhurst University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2007-2011 (Box 17, Folder 161)
  - Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology - Civil and Environmental Engineering Professorship and Undergraduate Scholarships, 1995-2000 (Box 17, Folder 162)
  - Sacred Heart University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1998-2000 (Box 17, Folder 163)
  - St. Catherine University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2004-2010 (Box 17, Folder 164)
  - St. Louis University - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1992 (Box 18, Folder 165)
  - St. Louis University - Graduate Fellowship, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 166)
  - St. Louis University - Graduate Fellowships, 1998-2000 (Box 18, Folder 167)
  - St. Louis University - Graduate Fellowships, 2000-2003 (Box 18, Folder 168)
  - St. Mary's College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2005-2013 (Box 18, Folder 169)
  - St. Michael's College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2003 (Box 18, Folder 170)
  - St. Norbert College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2001-2004 (Box 18, Folder 171)
  - Scripps College - Biology Professorship, 1998-2004 (Box 18, Folder 172)
  - Seattle University - Environmental Engineering Professorship, 1990-1999 (Box 18, Folder 173)
  - Seton Hill College - Undergraduate Sholarships, 1998-2002 (Box 19, Folder 174)
  - Spelman College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1994-1996 (Box 19, Folder 175)
  - Spelman College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 176)
  - Spelman College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2003 (Box 19, Folder 177)
  - Stanford University - Biology Professorship, 1989-1999 (Box 19, Folder 178)
  - State University of New York, Albany - Graduate Fellowships, 1998-2003 (Box 19, Folder 179)
  - Texas A&M University - Graduate Fellowships, 1992-1999 (Box 19, Folder 180)
  - Tufts University - Graduate Fellowships, 2001-2012 (Box 19, Folder 181)
  - Tulane University - Professorship (Withdrawn), 2000-2003 (Box 20, Folder 182)
  - University of California, Berkeley - Graduate Fellowships, 1989-1999 (Box 20, Folder 183)
  - University of California, Berkeley - Post Doctoral Fellowships, 2006-2013 (Box 20, Folder 184)
  - University of Chicago - Graduate Fellowships, 1989-1990 (Box 20, Folder 185)
  - University of Chicago - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1994 (Box 20, Folder 186)
  - University of Chicago - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1996-2004 (Box 20, Folder 187)
  - University of Dallas - Undergraduate Scholarship, 1995-1996 (Box 20, Folder 188)
  - University of Dallas - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1998-2000 (Box 20, Folder 189)
  - University of Dallas - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2001 (Box 20, Folder 190)
  - University of Dayton - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1992 (Box 20, Folder 191)
  - University of Dayton - Mechanical Engineering Professorship, 1993-2002 (Box 20, Folder 192)
  - University of Dayton - Undergraduate Scholarships and Graduate Fellowship, 1996-2000 (Box 21, Folder 193)
  - University of Dayton - Graduate Fellowships, 2000-2004 (Box 21, Folder 194)
  - University of Dayton - Graduate Fellowships, 2006-2013 (Box 21, Folder 195)
  - University of Denver - Undergraduate Scholarship and Graduate Fellowship, 1994-1997 (Box 21, Folder 196)
  - University of Denver - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2003 (Box 21, Folder 197)
  - University of Detroit, Mercy - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2004-2013 (Box 21, Folder 198)
  - University of Illinois - Graduate Fellowships, 1992-2001 (Box 21, Folder 199)
  - University of Maryland, College Park - Professorships, 2003-2014 (Box 21, Folder 200)
  - University of Michigan - Graduate Fellowships, 1990-1994 (Box 22, Folder 201)
  - University of Michigan - Graduate Fellowships, 1998-2001 (Box 22, Folder 202)
  - University of Portland - Geoscience Professorship, 1997-2004 (Box 22, Folder 203)
  - University of Portland - Physics Professorship, 2005-2012 (Box 22, Folder 204)
  - University of Richmond - Undergraduate Scholarship, 1994-1999 (Box 22, Folder 205)
  - University of St. Thomas - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1997-1999 (Box 22, Folder 206)
  - University of San Francisco - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2003 (Box 22, Folder 207)
  - University of Scranton - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1997-2001 (Box 22, Folder 208)
  - University of Texas, Austin - Civil Engineering Professorship, 1998-2003 (Box 22, Folder 209)
  - University of the Incarnate Word - Graduate Fellowship, 1998-2001 (Box 22, Folder 210)
  - University of Virginia - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1994-1999 (Box 23, Folder 211)
  - University of Washington - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1990-1999 (Box 23, Folder 212)
  - University of Washington - Professorship, 2001-2012 (Box 23, Folder 213)
  - University of Wisconsin, Madison - Electrical and Computer Engineering Professorship, 1990-2000 (Box 23, Folder 214)
  - Vassar College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1991-1999 (Box 23, Folder 215)
  - Villanova University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1992-1994 (Box 24, Folder 216)
  - Villanova University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2003 (Box 24, Folder 217)
  - Villanova University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 218)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Graduate Fellowships, 2006-2013 (Box 24, Folder 219)
  - Wake Forest University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1999-2009 (Box 24, Folder 220)
  - Washington University, St. Louis - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2006-2014 (Box 24, Folder 221)
  - Wellesley College - Physics Professorship, 1990-1995 (Box 24, Folder 222)
  - Wellesley College - Physics Professorship, 1992-1998 (Box 24, Folder 223)
  - Wellesley College - Mathematics Professorship, 1997-2004 (Box 24, Folder 224)
  - Wheeling Jesuit College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1993-1995 (Box 25, Folder 225)
  - Wheeling Jesuit College - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1996-1999 (Box 25, Folder 226)
  - Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute - Graduate Fellowships, 1999-2006 (Box 25, Folder 227)
  - Xavier University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 1997-1999 (Box 25, Folder 228)
  - Xavier University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2001-2010 (Box 25, Folder 229)
  - Xavier University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2004-2010 (Box 25, Folder 230)
  - Xavier University - Undergraduate Scholarships, 2007-2011 (Box 25, Folder 231)
  - Yale University - Physics Professorship, 1989-1997 (Box 25, Folder 232-233)
  - Yale University - Biochemistry Professorship, 1998-2008 (Box 25, Folder 234)
- Program Advisors, 1988-1989; 4; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - Nancy Hopkins, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 235)
  - Horace Judson, Johns Hopkins University, 1988-1989 (Box 26, Folder 236)
- Evaluation of the Clare Boothe Luce Program, 1999-2000; 5; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 10 Year Evaluation, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 237-238)
  - Evaluation Responses - Designated Institutions, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 239)
  - Evaluation Responses, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 240-242)